Guide to the Glenn Sitzman papers, 1940-2010.
Sitzman, Glenn papers, 1940-2010
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Glenn Sitzman papers, 1940-2010.
4272
Glenn L., Sitzman 1920-
40.4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, clippings, photographs, posters, currency
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, clippings, photograph albums, slides, and printed items of Glenn L. Sitzman. Also, political posters from the Philippines, ca. 1974, and currency reform posters from Nigeria, 1965, 1973.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Librarian.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, clippings, photograph albums, slides, and printed items of Glenn L. Sitzman. Also, political posters from the Philippines, ca. 1974, and currency reform posters from Nigeria, 1965, 1973.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Sitzman, Glenn L.,1920-
Subjects:
Gays--Puerto Rico.; Gays--Florida.; Librarians.
Places:
Philippines--Politics and government--1973-1986.; Nigeria--Politics and government--1960-1975.
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides; Broadsides; Photographs.; Slides (photographs).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 12, 14, 15, 19, 24, 26, 27, 31, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38, 40, 41, 44, 45, 46, 48, and 50 restricted until 2010 except by permission of the donor.
Family correspondence restricted until 2010.
Series List
Series I. Personal and Professional Papers
Series II. Family Papers - Genealogy
Series III. Family Papers - Restricted
Series IV. Personal Papers - Restricted
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Personal and Professional Papers
  - Clarion College Students, 1977-1984, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Huefner, Marge, 1982-1989, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Igwe, Ben - Nigerian librarian, 1965-1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Langlands, Bryan, 1967-1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Librarians, 1968-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Miscellany, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mohamedali, O.N. - library educator (1), 1967-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mohamedali, O.N. (2), 1976-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Nigeria - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1964-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Nitecki, Andre, Librarian and Lecturer on African Art, 1965-1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Nwafor, Bartholomew, Librarian University of Jos, Nigeria, 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Orimoloye, Stephen, Librarian University of Lagos, Nigeria, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Plumbe, Wilfred J., 1990-2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The Golden Pagoda Tree, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - RFD, 1981-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Trembley, William H., 1967-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Uganda - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1966-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - White, Dr. Carl M., Librarian; Ruth Bennet White, Nutritionist, 1963-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Zaehringer, David, Librarian, Columbia University, 1965-1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1978 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1980 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Political Activism & Newsletter Correspondence, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 24-25)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1982 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1983 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1986 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, etc., 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Reese, Samuel N. - prison correspondence:, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Round Robins, 1965-1994 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Gay Round Robins, 1979-1987 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Library-Related Correspondence, 1964-1978 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Librarians - Foreign & American Overseas B-D, 1964-1981 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Librarians - Foreign & American Overseas F-K, 1967-1974 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Librarians - Foreign & American Overseas L-V, 1966-1978 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - University of Guyana, 1967-1987 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Makerere University, 1964-1967 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Makerere University (Uganda), 1966-1982 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - British Council International Course in Librarianship, 1967-1974 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Philippine Library Conference, 1974 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Cumbie, Edward, files, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cumbie, Edward: letters to Glenn Sitzman, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cumbie, Edward: letters to Glenn Sitzman, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cumbie, Edward: letters to Glenn Sitzman, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Glenn Sitzman, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs - album pages; Photograph albums (9) (Box 2, Folder 6-14)
  - Adler, Irving and Joyce Sparer, Educators, 1969-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Amos, Geraldine Odester - American librarian (former colleague in Nigeria), 1966-2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Aponte, Anna, 1995-1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Araujo, Jorge - Gay activist, Mexico City, 1981-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Atchia, Michael and Paula, Educators, Mauritius, 1965-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Ayagere, Solomon - Staff, National Library of Nigeria, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Baker, Don P. (pen pal), 1991-2002 (Box 3, Folder 7-12)
  - Branyon, Jack Wilson, 1928-1955 - friend and lover, 1951-1955 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Brown, Frederick (Frenchie) - prison correspondence, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Calva, José Rafael, 1981-1997 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
  - Calva-Pratt, José Rafael, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Campbell, Danial J. - friend, 1967-1994 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Carr, Kathryn P.(Penn) - librarian, 1966-2000 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Carson, Brandon, 1982, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Clark, Eugene, 1972-1980 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Clough, Evalyn - librarian former classmate & colleague at Columbia University, 1966-1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Cole Family, 1970-1982 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Conover, Helen F. - formerly Africana Librarian at the Library of Congress, 1967-1978 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Cotto, Orlando, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Crissey, Lucy M. - formerly Ass't Dean, School of Library Science, Columbia U., 1961-1978 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - David, Conrado D. - Filipino librarian, 1968-1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Davis, Anne, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Diaz, George Daniel Gonzalez - Correspondence with bank, documents, photos, 1961-1971 (Box 3, Folder 29-31)
  - Dorfman, Marcia - librarian, 1972-1981 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Feliciano, Freddie, 1994-1999 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Fowler, Miriam, housekeeper in Guyana, 1969-1982 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Gugliara, Lawrence - prison correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Gyebi, Alfred K. - Ghanaian librarian, 1969-1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Hall, Lyle C. - gay pen pal plus people he introduced, 1985-1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Harris, Priscilla Taylor - formerly Library Advisor to the Federal Gov't of Nigeria (American born in New Zealand), 1965-1969 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Hogg, Frank N. - Principal, College of Librarianship, Wales, 1966-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Imbruglio, Michael A., 2001 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Johnston, James - friend (formerly known as James Aron Delaire, 1979-2004 (Box 7, Folder 7-8)
  - Katayama, Takatoshi - Japanese librarian, also his daughters Mikiko (older) and Atsuko, 1967-2003 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Kim, Bong Hi - concert pianist and teacher, 1973-1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Koski, George and Golda (George - music teacher), 1970-1998 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Krzys, Richard - professor, University of Pittsburgh, 1972-1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Kubo, Masami, Japanese student, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Lancour, Harold - formerly Dean, Lib. School, Pittsburgh, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - LeFresne, Grace - diplomat, 1969-1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Manuel, Rev. Elva E., 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Mayol, Josefina - librarian, 1970-1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Mbadugha, R[obert] Okey - Nigerian businessman, 1966-1993 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Mbadugha, R. Okey (2), 1975-1997 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - McGrath, Michael - pen pal, 1988-1995 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - McNatt, Zora - friend, 1967-1987 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Medina-Montesinos, Francisco (pen pal), 1990-1996 (Box 7, Folder 22-25)
  - Nagata, Professor Masao, Japanese educator, 1979-2003 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Noble, Marjorie - British Council librarian, 1966-1995 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Parker, Richard K. - educator, 1979-2004 (Box 7, Folder 28-31)
  - Penco (Penko), Luciano (pen pal, Yugoslavia), 1960-1972 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Penn, Charles D. - sketches, 1944, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Pizer, Irwin - medical librarian & former student at SLS, Columbia University, 1963-1971 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Raimi, Sabiu (later Owobowale) - former driver (correspondence 1964-1972) Owobowale, Rotimi (formerly Raimi) (Sabiu's son) (correspondence Oct. 1982-, 1964-1993 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Ramer, James - librarian, 1966-1973 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Rao, Krishna - librarian includes correspondence with his nephew Shantharama Somayaji, 1968-1985 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Rosete, Jorge, Jose Manuel Duprat - friends in Mexico, 1981-1989 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Rozman, Janez, pen pal, Yugoslavia, 1960-1962 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Schrader, Donald - pen pal, 1983-1995 (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
  - Shelley, Lee - friend, 1973-1996 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Mary Carter - librarian, poet, 1973-1981 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Max, 1985-1992 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Stephens, Donald - friend, 1970-1996 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Stewart, Mildred (Mrs. Havis L.) - librarian, 1966-1996 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Stigler, Mrs. H. W., 1968-1987 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Takeuchi, Satoru - library educator, 1973-1998 (Box 28, Folder 14-17)
  - Tauber, Maurice F., - formerly professor, SLS, Columbia U., 1961-1980 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Terry, Altha E. - formerly Head Cataloger, Columbia U., c.1966 [1971] (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - Vining, Donald, Author of A Gay Diary, 1981-1984 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Ware, Donald (Tino), 1982-1998 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Wilkinson, Eoin - librarian, 1968-1992 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Williams, Lee H., Jr. - librarian, Daniel Barreto, 1967-1996 (Box 28, Folder 23-25)
  - Williams, Lee from Glenn Sitzman (gift of Lee Williams), 1993-1994 (Box 28, Folder 26-27)
  - Wray, Wendell - GSLIS, University of Pittsburgh, 1973-1974 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Zimmerman, Irene - librarian, 1963-1996 (Box 28, Folder 29)
  - Baumgardt, Manfred; Schwules Museum; Berlin, 2002 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1979 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Library-related, 1960-1963 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Non-Library, 1965-1987 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-2000 (Box 37, Folder 5-6)
  - Miscellaneous political, charitable, 2000-2007 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Political clippings (mostly from Florida newspapers, 2004 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Political miscellany and clippings, 2004 (Box 37, Folder 9-10)
  - Non-gay friends, 1995-2000 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Christmas cards from non-gay friends, 1994-1995 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - The Move from Ponce [PR] to Naples [FL], 1995 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Cedars Home for Children, Lincoln, NE, 1995-2006 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Car: Puerto Rico and Florida, 1991-2004 (Box 37, Folder 15-16)
  - Columbia University, 2003 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Gay Credit Card Company: Uncommon Clout, 1995-1998 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Gay Long Distance Company: Community Spirit, 1995-1999 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1998-2005 (Box 37, Folder 20-24)
  - Homosexuality and related topics, 2003-2004 (Box 37, Folder 25-26)
  - In the life, 2004-2005 (Box 37, Folder 27-28)
  - Organizations, 2001-2003 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Gay Organizations, 2003-2004 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Misc. organizations, letters, etc., 2005 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Equality, 2004-2005 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - RFD and other publications information, 2001-2005 (Box 37, Folder 33-34)
  - (3 year) Telephone log, 1998-2000 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - (3 year) Travel logs, birthdays, etc., 1998-2000 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - (3 year) Weather log, 1998-2000 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - AIDS - educational materials, P.R., 1998 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Baylor University - gay alumni, 1988-1996 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Gay Contact letters, 1986-1987 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Gay Contact letters, 1987-1988 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Gay Contact letters, 1990-1991 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Gay friends, 1988-1991 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Gay friends, 1992-1997 (Box 32, Folder 7-8)
  - Gay friends, pen-pals, contact letters, 1991-1996 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Gay friends and contact letters, 1995-1997 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Prison correspondence, 1983-1990 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Gay correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Gay correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Gay correspondence and material, 1987-1988 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Gay papers and correspondence, 1989 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Gay clippings, 1998 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Gay organizations, 1997-1998 (Box 32, Folder 17-21)
  - Gay group, Naples, FL, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous gay organizations (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and materials, 1971-1988 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1993-1997 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Clarion University, 1998-1999 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Political, 1995-1996 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous political, charitable, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Cultural Event, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, 1997 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Gay Social Network, Naples, Florida, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
  - Gay Switchboard of Harrisburg, 1995 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Human Rights Campaign Fund, 1987-1994 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Lambda Legal Defense Fund, 1993-1994 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - The Loving Brotherhood, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
  - Mariposa Education & Research Foundation, 1987-1991 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - National Gay & Lesbian Task Force, 1987-1991 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - National Gay Rights Advocates, 1987-1994 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Paz y Liberacion, 1987-1994 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - RFD (see also Box 1 Folder 14), 1990-1993 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - SAGE (Senior Action in a Gay Environment), 1987-1990 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - El Colectivo de Concientización Gay (gay organization in San Juan, Puerto Rico), 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Gay Organizations, 1985-1991 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Articles on Gays, 1969, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Gay Material, 1981-1992 (Box 18, Folder 17-21)
  - Gay publications, 1989-1991 (Box 18, Folder 22-23)
  - Gay organizations, publications, etc., 1989-1995 (Box 18, Folder 24-26)
  - Gay organizations, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 27-29)
  - Miscellaneous gay, 1992-1994 (Box 18, Folder 30-31)
  - Sexuality - various aspects, 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Sexuality, abuse, gay general, 1995-1996 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Sexuality - gay police in P.R., 1994-1995 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Sexuality - rape, sodomy, murder trial, 1994-1996 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Gays in the Military, 1993-1995 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Sexuality - AIDS; Sexuality, AIDS, etc. - Puerto Rico; Sexuality, AIDS, etc. - Florida; Sexuality - Gay police, Puerto Rico; Newspaper clippings, etc. related to AIDS, homosexuality, etc. taken mostly from Puerto Rican publications; Photo album 1996 U.S. Presidential campaign (Box 39, Folder 1-20)
  - Photo album (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Images of Puerto Rico, text and photographs by Roger A. LaBrucherie (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - 3 Photo albums (Box 61)
  - The Best of In the Life, 2006-2006; DVD-710 (Box 61)
  - box of holiday items from "Meals on Wheels" (Box 61)
  - "Cardinal" window ornament (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Gay greeting cards (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
  - Christmas cards from gay friends; Cassette with songs (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - International greeting cards: Argentina, Australia, Caribbean, Egypt, Europe, Ghana, Hong Kong, India, Italy, Japan, Nigeria, Philippines, Puerto Rico, Swaziland, Turkey, Uganda, United Kingdom, Venezuela, Yugoslavia, Zambia (Box 30)
  - First Baptist Church, Clinton, OK, 1942-1944 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Baylor University, 1947-1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Columbia University, 1958-1997 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Ford Foundation, 1963-1968 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Housing - Nigeria, Uganda, Guyana, 1965-1968 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Car - Uganda, Guyana, 1966-1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - American Library Association, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Servants, 1965-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Job Hunting, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Japan, 1974, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Chubu Institute of Technology, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Philippine Library Conference, 1974-1981 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Uganda - Miscellaneous; Japan, 1964-1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - White House Conference on Aging, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Echoes from The Hill (Southwestern State College Alumni Newsletter), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Staff, National Library of Nigeria (photograph, with identification), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Librarians met during British Council International Course in Librarianship, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence, personal, 1992-1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence "official", 2004 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence "official and friendly mail", 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Clarion State College - Correspondence "letters from Clarion, Pa.", 2001-2007 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Clarion State College - Memorabilia, 1969-1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Clarion State College - Memorabilia - Correspondence, 1970-1992 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Clarion State College - Miscellaneous Items, 1971-1991 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Clarion University - Sitzman Award Fund, foreign students, 1975-1995 (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
  - Clarion University - Sitzman Award winners, 1996-2005 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Clarion University, 1989-2009 (Box 6, Folder 17-25)
  - Clarion University [Gay News], 2000-2003 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - GIACT (Gay Information and Concerns Team - Clarion College) - includes 3 cassette recordings, 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Miscellaneous Non-Gay, 1987-1994 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Non-Gay, 1989-1997 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Nyarko, George, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Art Collection, 1966-1983 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Broadsides and posters, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous items, 1967-1981 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Langston University, 1989-1991 (Box 22, Folder 2-3)
  - Building a House in Puerto Rico, ca. 1981 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Move to Puerto Rico, 1983-1984 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, programs related to cultural events, 1988-1989 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Cultural events, 1989-1994 (Box 22, Folder 7-10)
  - Cultural events in Puerto Rico, at the Museo de Arte de Ponce and elsewhere, 1989-1996 (Box 22, Folder 11-22)
  - University of Puerto Rico Graduate School of Library Service, 1988-1993 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Felisa Rincon - Puerto Rico's grand lady, feminist, 1994-1995 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Poems, 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Short stories, 1940-1960 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
  - "The Diffused Humanism of Ovid in Elizabethan Literature", 1947 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - "The Importance of Osorio in the Formative Years of S.T. Coleridge" - student paper, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "Uganda's University Library," College and Research Libraries Vol. 29, No. 3, May, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - "Wedding in 'Santeria'," R.F.D. article mss., 1990 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Published article, unpublished lecture, lecture notes, 1976, 1980, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Unpublished article on culture role/shock, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Articles, letters to the editor, etc., 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Publications by GLS, 1995-1996 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - African Libraries - manuscript (see Box 31 for annotated copy), 1988 (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
  - African Libraries - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1982-2003 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - African Libraries - Publicity, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Original Photographic Essay, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - In Search of a Publisher, 1982-1985 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence- Scarecrow Press, 1982-1994 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - African Libraries - Search for Information, 1982-1984 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - African Libraries - Photographs, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Christmas greetings with references to African Libraries, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Reviews, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Photographs used in African Libraries, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Photographs not used - Public Libraries - West Africa, Ghana, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Not used - Public Libraries - West Africa (Nigeria), n.d. (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Not used - Public Libraries - East Africa, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Not used - Cultural Libraries, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Not used - Academic Libraries, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Not used - Special Features, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Bibliography of Library Management in Sub-Saharan Africa; Correspondence, notes, work pages (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - Bibliography, 1986-1987 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography, 1988 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Bibliography, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Bibliography, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Reprints (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Receipts: Nigeria, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Receipts: Africa, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Receipts: Miscellaneous expenses relating to sabbatical trip to Africa, 1980 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Clarion Borough and Pennsylvania State taxes, 1970-1978 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Passports & travel documents Pa. driver's license, 1960-1980 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Car - Puerto Rico, 1988-1995 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Apartment - Clarion, Pa., 1968-1981 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Banks, Bonds, Insurance, 1965-1998 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Bank Accounts, 1986-1993 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Health, 1978-1996 (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
  - Health - reading material, 1972-1987 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Insurance - TIAA/CREF, 1961-1996 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Papers and correspondence relating to lots bought in Puerto Rico, 1981-1985 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Retirement, 1980-1989 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Insurance, 1985-1996 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Homeowners insurance, 1985-1991 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Telephone at Mayaguez & problems at Mayaguez and Ponce, 1993-1995 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Travel Correspondence, 1992-1994 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Retirement centers, 1991-1993 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - House at Road 105, Km. 9.0 Barrio Limon, PR - Mayaguez, Oct. 1985-Aug. 1992, 1985-1995 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Taxes: related to lots in Montosa, house & 2 acres in Limón & some income, 1984-1995 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Social Security, 1982-1991 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Baylor University - M.A. diploma, 1947 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Columbia University - M.L.S. diploma, 1956 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - White House Conference on Aging Medal, 1981 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Bracelet - Clarion University GIACT - retirement gift, 1982 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - "Love an Older Person Today" pin (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - "Clarion Proud" pin, Pi Kappa Alpha pin (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Letter opener (1910) brought from Italy by Jack Branyon in 1951 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Cap advertising gay discos in PR (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Oklahoma Baptist University diploma (Box 33, Folder 9)